(いの)はぁ。
何の役にも立てなかった。
I was totally useless...
そればかりか
迷惑ばかりかけて。
In fact, I was just in the way...
リーさんは どんなときもポジティブで
ひと汗かけば➡
Lee-san, you're always so positive and
once you work up a sweat,
ヤなことも
すぐ忘れちゃうでしょ？
you're able to forget
every negative thing, aren't you?
私は そうはいかなくて。
I'm just not like that...
(リー)これは 汗ではありません！
悔し涙です！
This is not sweat.
These are tears of frustration!
今度こそ お役に立ちたいと➡
This time, at least, I wanted to be useful
and I had prepared thoroughly!
万全の準備を
してるとこじゃないですかぁ！
わ わかったわよ！
私だって 今度こそは！
I-I know how you feel.
This time, I also wanted...
(サクラ)カカシ先生！
Kakashi-sensei!
(サクラ)ナル…！
(ヒナタ)ナルト君は!?
- Na-!
- Where's Naruto-kun?!
そんな…。
その子は？
That's...
Who's that boy?
(カカシ)恐らく 三尾を
操ることができるという➡
Probably... the one who can control
the Three-Tails...
特殊な能力の持ち主が
この子だ。
This boy is the one with
that special power.
三尾は 湖に消えてしまったが
これで終わりってわけじゃない。
The Three-Tails has disappeared
into the lake,
but this isn't over by any means.
封印班の回復を待って➡
We'll wait for the Sealing team
to recover,
再度 結界四方封陣を行う。
だが…。
and then we'll attempt the
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier again.
However...
今 この子を
動かすことはできない。
we can't move this child right now.
彼が回復ししだい➡
When he regains consciousness,
もっと安全な場所に移動し
態勢を整える。
we'll move to a safer spot
and make preparations.
その間に ナルトを捜索する。
Meanwhile, we need to find Naruto.
ナルト…。
大丈夫よ！
Naruto...
Don't worry.
ナルトのことだから
湖で平泳ぎでもしてるわよ！
Knowing Naruto, he's probably in
the lake doing the breaststroke.
(カカシ)ヤマト サイ キバ ヒナタ。
Yamato, Sai, Kiba, Hinata...
そしてオレの５人で
ナルト捜索にあたる。
And myself.
The five of us will search for Naruto.
シズネ。 ナルトが
ケガをしていた場合に備えて➡
Shizune, you come with us
just in case Naruto is injured.
キミにも ついてきてもらう。
Right.
サクラ いのは この子の治療を頼む。
Sakura and Ino will treat the boy.
残りの者は
その警護にあたってくれ。
The rest of you will keep guard.
敵は必ず
この子を奪い返しに来る。
The enemy is sure to return
to take the boy.
渡しはしません！
必ず守りぬいてみせますとも！
I won't let them!
I will protect the boy, no matter what!
みんな。 気を引き締め
それぞれの任務にあたってくれ！
Everyone, stay alert and
carry out your mission!
白眼！
Byakugan!
ナルト君…。
Naruto-kun...
(ヤマト)クッ！
(シズネ)ヒナタやキバ君を擁しても➡
What if we can't find Naruto,
even with Hinata and Kiba-kun with us?
見つからなかったら…。
いい？ 三尾封印のあとだから
疲労が激しいと思うけど➡
Listen. I know we just tried to seal
the Three-Tails and it's totally exhausting,
慎重にチャクラをコントロールして。
わかってる。
but we have to be extremely careful
with our Chakra Control.
I know. I will redeem myself.
汚名返上よ。 絶対に
この子を… 助けるんだから。
I'm absolutely going...
to save this boy.
では ボクは せめて
２人のチャクラコントロールが➡
Well then, the least I can do is make sure
your Chakra Control goes well,
うまくいくように
願掛けのスクワットを…。
and do squats of prayer...!
気が散る。
あっ… はい。
I can't concentrate!
Okay.
(テンテン)私たちは
護衛にあたるんでしょ？
We're supposed to be guarding them.
そ… そうでした！
Th-That's right!
(テンテン)かたまっていても
しようがないわ。
It's not smart to stay clustered together.
ここには シノもいることだし
私たちは裏にまわりましょう。
Shino is here.
Let's go around the back.
ボクは… ボクは…。
(テンテン)アンタは屋根の上よ。
What about... me?!
You keep watch on top of the roof.
了解です。
Got it!
《シノ : 蟲たちが
これほどまでに弱るとは…。
The insects are drastically weakened...
これも 三尾のチャクラの影響か…》
Is this also due to
the Three-Tail's Chakra?
(ナルト)ここは…。
Where is this...?
そうだ…
三尾の野郎に飲み込まれて…。
I know! I was swallowed by
that Three-Tails!
てことは ここはヤツの腹ん中かよ？
Which means I'm inside his belly...!
かてぇ！
ったく 胃 荒れすぎだっつうの。
It's so hard!
Cripes, his stomach is awful!
What does he eat anyway?
何 食ってやがんだよ。
あっ オレか…。
Oh... me...
お前は…。
You're...!
コイツ…。
Why you--!
(紅蓮)お前に幽鬼丸は渡さない！
I won't let you have Yuukimaru!
幽鬼丸は…。
- Yuukimaru is...!
- Die!
死ね!!
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Strange Bedfellows
(濡羅吏)鱗児！
Rinji!
(鬼霧)テメエ どういうこった！
戦闘中に ばっくれるなんてよ！
Why you-! What's going on?!
Leaving us in the trenches during a fight!
(鬼鳳)お陰で
オレたちは この有様だぜ。
We went through hell thanks to you!
(鱗児)まあ そう言うな。
紅蓮さんから➡
Now, now. I got an urgent summons
from Guren-san, so I had no choice.
緊急の呼び出しを受けたら
行かざるをえないだろ。
ふん！
な… 何を…。
Huh? Wh-What?!
ふむ…。
この野郎…。
Why you--!
(鬼霧)な… なんだよ。
Wh-What?!
失礼ね！ 人の顔をジロジロと…。
ふん。
It's rude to stare like that!
戦場では 刻一刻と状況が変わる。
ちょ… ちょっと！
Humph... Things change every second
in the battlefield.
H-Hey!
文句ばかり言うんじゃない。
(濡羅吏)どこに行くのよ？
Quit complaining.
鱗児！
Where are you going?
Rinji...!
なんか…
おかしくねえか？ 鱗児。
Isn't he... acting strange? That Rinji.
たるんでるのよ。
完全な敵前逃亡じゃない。
He's lost it. Running away
in the face of the enemy.
(カブト)誰が敵前逃亡だって？
Who ran away from the enemy?
あっ… いえ… その…。
Uh... no... Well...
もう… また ジロジロと…。
Cripes... Quit staring!
チッ… 鱗児といい 何なんだよ。
You and Rinji... What's with you?
アンタ 自分の目を
鏡で見たことあるか？
Have you ever looked at
your eyes in the mirror?
人間を見る目じゃねえよ。
そりゃあ。
They're not eyes that look at humans.
フフフフ…。
キミたち このままじゃ
死んじゃうよ。
(３人)えっ!?
At this rate, you guys will die.
そ… そんなに悪いのか オレたち。
A-Are we that bad?!
ウソだろ!?
いやだ 冗談じゃ…。
Liar!
No! You're just kidding...
(カブト)冗談じゃない。
ない？
I'm not kidding.
チャクラの流れが メチャクチャ。
You're not?
The flow of Chakra is all over the place...
いや この場合 破壊に向かって
進んでると言うべきか…。
In this case, I'd say you're heading
straight towards destruction.
破壊…。
(カブト)いやぁ 恐ろしい敵と
戦ったものだね。
Destruction?
My, my.
You fought against a terrifying foe...
例えば鬼鳳 キミの場合は➡
You, Kihou... In your case,
そうだなぁ
あと２時間ももたずに ボン。
I'd say... you have less
than two hours left and boom!
うっ… うわぁ！
マジかよ… オレは どうなんだ!?
オレは！
Are you serious?!
What about me? Am I...?
やめて！ 自分の死に方なんて
知りたくもないわ！
Stop! I don't want to know
how I'm going to die!
し… 死にたくない！
なにとぞ お助けください カブト様！
I-I don't want to die!
Please save me, Kabuto!
オ… オレもです！
どうか助けてください！
M-Me too! Please save me!
ボンは イヤだ！ ボンは イヤだ!!
I don't wanna go "boom"! No "boom"!
いくら頼まれても
ボクの医療忍術にも➡
No matter how much you beg,
できることと できないことが…。
there are things I can and
can't do with my Medical Ninjutsu...
あっ！
(３人)えっ!?
Ah...
いやぁ ダメだ ダメだ。
- Huh?!
No... No, I can't.
大事な仲間に
そんなことはできない。
I can't do such a thing
to my precious comrades!
そんなこと！
その そんなことってヤツを➡
"Such a thing"?!
オレたちにしてください！
なんでもします！
Please do "such a thing" to us!
どんなことでも
耐えてみせます！
We'll do anything.
We'll endure anything!
(鬼鳳)ボンは イヤだ！
I don't wanna go "bon"!
フン…。
(カブト)キミたちが
そこまで言うなら…。
Well, since you insist...
- Huh?
((アイツは 利用されてるんだ！
He's being used. He believes
there's someone he can return to...
いつか帰るべき場所だって
信じてるヤツに➡
必ず 必ず裏切られる…。
But he's sure to be betrayed.
そうなったら アイツは➡
When that happens...
帰る場所が なくなっちまうんだ。
He won't have anywhere to go...
思っている人がいるところが
帰るべき場所だって言うんなら➡
If wherever someone thinks of you
is the place you return to...
(オレは… オレが アイツのことを
思い続けてやる！))
Then...
I'll keep thinking of him.
(サクラ)ナルトが言ってたのは
この子だったのね。
So Naruto was talking about this boy...
えっ？
あっ…。
Huh?
ナルトは 大丈夫。
きっと この子のことを➡
Oh...!
Naruto is okay. I'm sure he's somewhere
thinking about this boy...
どこかで思い続けて…。
(幽鬼丸)うぅ…。
(幽鬼丸)あっ… ここは？
大丈夫。 これからは
私たちが あなたを守るから。
Where am I?
It's okay. We're going to protect you
from now on.
守る…？
Protect...?
あっ！ ない… ない！
It's gone! It's gone!
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
何か なくなってるの？
ない…。
Is something missing?
It's gone...!
ない！
Gone...!
(幽鬼丸)ない！ ない!!
Gone... Gone...!
((ここは…。
This is...
あっ… あれは 幽鬼丸？
That's...
じゃ… じゃあ あなたは…！
Yuukimaru...?
Then... Then... you're...
私… 私は 許してもらえるの？
I...
I'm forgiven?
あなたは 私を…。
Have you...
(大蛇丸)人を殺しておいて➡
You have the gall to ask such a thing
after killing someone...
なんて虫のいいことを
言うのかしら。
許されるですって？
イヤ！
Forgive you...?
そんなことは
あるわけないじゃない！
No...!
Absolutely not!
(うわぁ～!!))
(紅蓮)やめて… やめてくれ。
Stop... Please stop...!
わ 私は…。
I...
傷が…。
お前が手当てをしたのか。
My wound...
どういうつもりだ？
何を企んでいる。
Did you treat it?
What's the big idea?
What are you scheming?!
べつに。
ウソをつくな！
Nothing...!
敵が意識を失っている。
Don't lie!
忍のお前が
そのチャンスをムダにする…。
Your enemy lies unconscious!
Why would you, a Ninja,
pass up the chance to...!
オレは 戦えねえヤツを
手にかけるような➡
I wouldn't do a shameful thing like hurting
someone who's unable to fight!
そんな卑怯なことはしねえ。
幽鬼丸は？
Where's Yuukimaru?!
近くにはいない。
あのとき三尾に飲み込まれたのは
たぶん オレたちだけだ。
He's not close by.
Back then, I think we were the only two
that Three-Tails swallowed.
じゃあ 幽鬼丸は まだ湖に…。
Then Yuukimaru is still by the lake...
あるいは お前たちの手に
渡っちまったか➡
Either your guys got him...
それとも オレの仲間の誰かに
助けられているか。
or one of my comrades saved him.
だったら 一刻も早く
ここを脱出して➡
Then I have to get out of here
immediately and find out.
それを確かめなきゃならない。
お前と私との戦いは必然だ。
So it's imperative that we fight.
私はお前を倒して ここを出る。
I'm going to defeat you
and get out of here.
お前がここを出ることは
叶わない。
You won't leave here...
unless you can defeat me.
私を倒さぬかぎりはな。
だよな オレもそう思うってばよ。
That's true...
I was just thinking the same thing...
《でもな…》
But...
ん？
な なんだ？
Huh?
Wh-What...?
うわっ！ でっけえ虫。
Huge bugs...?!
…って こりゃ ちっけえ三尾だ。
These are... mini-Three-Tails!
うわっ！
あぁ もう！
Aw, jeez!
何をする？
What're you doing?!
うわぁ～!!
私の晶遁で…。
できるわけねえだろ。
I'll use my Crystal Style...!
そのケガじゃムリだ。
You can't! Remember?
Not with that injury!
離せ！
Let go!
自分で走る。
I can run by myself!
(幽鬼丸)ない ない。
どうしたの？ 何探してるの？
It's gone...! Gone!
What's the matter?
What are you looking for?
あ… あっ！
あった あったよ！
Found it! I found it!
ほら。
きれいな水晶。
See!
傷もついてない よかった。
It's a pretty crystal...
It's not even scratched...
紅蓮さんは無事だよ。
I'm so glad. Guren-san is all right.
紅蓮さんって…。
Guren-san...?
《もしかして ナルトが言ってた
この子が思ってる人のこと？》
Could it be the person Naruto spoke of,
the one this boy thinks of?
ウフフフ… あっ！
大丈夫？
Oh...!
紅蓮さんは無事だよ
ウフフ あっ！
Are you all right?!
Guren is all right.
この子 いったい…。
This boy... What's with...
((アイツは利用されてるんだ。
He's being used.
いつか帰るべき場所だって
信じてるヤツに➡
He believes there's someone
he can return to...
(必ず… 必ず 裏切られる))
But he's sure to be betrayed.
アハハ！
大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
なぜ…。
Why?
なぜ 私を助けようとする？
Why are you trying to help me?
オレは キズを負った敵に…。
I don't fight an injured enemy...
あの三尾もどきに 片づけさせれば
よかったじゃないか！
You could've left me for
those Three-Tails back there...
そんなもん見たら
気持悪いじゃねえかよ！
That would be disgusting to watch!
フッ甘いな お前。
You're... naïve...
フン！
私なら 必ずお前を殺している。
Humph!
Had it been me, you'd be dead by now.
そして なんとしても
ここを出て 幽鬼丸を…。
And I'd leave this place...
and look for Yuukimaru.
そんなに幽鬼丸がほしいのかよ？
You want Yuukimaru that badly?
大蛇丸のために。
For Orochimaru's sake?!
お前たちこそ
幽鬼丸の力に気づき➡
Well, what about you guys?
捕らえようと
しているじゃないか！
You discovered Yuukimaru's powers
and now you want him!
三尾を手に入れれば
途方もない軍事力が➡
After all, taking the Three-Tails
means that the Hidden Leaf Village
木ノ葉に備わるからな。
will be in possession of
enormous military power.
んなもん オレたちには必要ねえ！
We don't need such a thing!
ウソだ！ すでに木ノ葉は尾獣を…。
Liar! The Hidden Leaf Village already
has the Nine-Tails
九尾と その人柱力を
手に入れているだろうが！
as well as the Jinchuriki!
そんな力を持つお前たちが
大蛇丸様を…。
People like you with that kind of power
have no right...
私たちを 非難する資格などない！
to criticize Lord Orochimaru...
or us!
オレが その人柱力だってばよ！
And I'm that Jinchuriki!
Wha--?!
だけど オレは この力を使わねえ。
But I...
don't use this power.
コイツの力は とんでもねえ。
The Nine-Tails has this incredible power
that I can't control with my own strength.
オレの力じゃ
コイツを コントロールできねえんだ。
知らねえうちに
仲間を傷つけることだってある。
I've hurt my comrades before
I even realized it happened...
だから オレは コイツの力を使わねえ。
That's why... I don't use its power.
オレが あんなこと言わなけりゃ…。
If I hadn't told him such a thing...
((思ってるヤツがいるところが
帰ってくる場所なんだ。
The place where someone thinks of you,
that's where home is.
じゃあ 誰かが
ボクのことを思ってくれたら➡
So if someone is thinking about me,
then that's the place I go back to?
(そこが
ボクの帰る場所になるんだね))
お前が 言ったのか？
You told him?
でもよ いくら
思われてたって➡
But no matter how much someone
thinks of him...
大蛇丸のために
幽鬼丸の力を使って➡
If you're gonna use Yuukimaru
for Orochimaru's sake...
三尾を
コントロールさせようってんじゃ➡
to make him control the Three-Tails...
ダメだろ。
That's not right.
オレは 幽鬼丸を
尾獣に近づけたくねえんだよ。
I don't want Yuukimaru to get near
a Tailed Beast.
オレみたいになっちまったら…。
If he becomes like me...
違う 私は そんなことはさせない。
No! I won't let Yuukimaru do
such a thing.
信用できねえ。
I don't believe you.
あの子には帰る場所が必要なんだ。
He needs a place to return to.
あの子の母親が死んだとき➡
When his mother died,
Yuukimaru lost the place to return to...
幽鬼丸は 帰る場所をなくした。
だから 私が代わりに…。
So I'm taking her place...!
大蛇丸の仲間が何言ってやがる！
You should talk!
You're a follower of Orochimaru.
オレは幽鬼丸に お前の帰る場所は
ここじゃねえって➡
I have to tell Yuukimaru that
you're not  the place to return to!
言わなきゃなんねえんだ！
だったら それでもいい！
でも 私にとって あの子が…➡
Then that's fine!
But... for me...
幽鬼丸が 私の帰る場所なんだ！
that boy...
Yuukimaru is...
the place for me to return to!
お前…。
You...
とにかく ここで言い合ってる
場合じゃねえようだな。
Anyway...
this isn't the place
to argue about that.
お前が倒れてる間に
１人であたりを調べてみた。
While you were unconscious,
I took a look around.
けど中は複雑で 出口らしいもんは
見つけらんなかった。
It's really complex in there and
I couldn't find anything like an exit.
でも 手わけして探せば。
手わけ？
But if we split up and search...
お前と私 ２人でか？
Split up?
You and me... The two of us...?
もっとだ。 1,000人は必要だな。
More than that. We need a thousand guys.
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
キミたち３人の使命は
木ノ葉から幽鬼丸を奪還すること。
You three are ordered to take
Yuukimaru away from the Hidden Leaf.
その目的を
果たすためなら何をしてもいい。
Resort to any means necessary
in order to succeed.
その力
存分に楽しんでくるといいよ。
That power...
go and enjoy it
until you're satisfied.
《ヒナタ : ナルト君…》
Naruto...!
《ナルト…》
第１回 ナルト杯争奪！ 何か
わけのわかんない場所脱出記念！
Naruto...
Here's to the First Naruto Cup Challenge!
The Let's-Get-Out-of-This-Crazy-Place;
Find-an-Exit Contest!
出口探し大会！ いってみよっか！
Let's do it!
お～っ！
- Yeah!
位置について。
In your positions!
よ～い ドン！
Ready, set...!
Go!
こんだけの数で探せば 出口なんて
すぐに見つかるってばよ！
With this many guys searching,
finding the exit is a cinch!
よし オレが見つけるぜ！ オレだ！
All right! I'll find it!
《何としてもここを出て
幽鬼丸に…》
No, I will!
Whatever I do, I have to get out...
and find Yuukimaru...
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
わかった わかったよ
紅蓮さんのいるところ！
I know!
I know where Guren-san is!
えっ？
きっと ナルトさんも一緒だよ。
Huh?
I'm sure Naruto-san is with her!
三尾のお腹の中にいる！
They're in the Three-Tail's tummy!
ウフフッ。
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu wo mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
beyond a great number of promises
ikutsu mono yakusoku no sono ue ni tatte wa
are the words that spilled over from the day as I reflect upon them
kamishimeru ano hi koboreochita kotoba
it's as though I made a vow which expresses these feelings into words
komerareta omoi wa chikai no you de
then it would link the befinning with the present day
kuchi ni sureba ima to hajimari wo tsunagu
it's not in my dreams
yume de wa nakute
that place doesn't exist in a fantasy world either
esoragoto no sekai de mo nai basho de sa
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu no mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukete
embracing the long path ahead
sono zutto saki wo toraeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
Next Episode
According to Yuukimaru,
Guren the Crystal Style user is alive...
And he says that Naruto and this Guren
were swallowed by the Three-Tails?
That story may have some truth to it.
But how do you know that Guren is okay?
If something happens to Guren,
this crystal will break, as well...
But it doesn't mean that Naruto is okay.
We need to believe he's still alive
and find the Three-Tails first.
Guidepost of the
Camellia
Next time: "Guidepost of the Camellia"